# **OĞUZCAN TURAN**

Computer Engineer

a. Kırkkonaklar District, 06610, Çankaya-Ankara, TURKEY

e. can.turan.10@gmail.com / oguzcan.turan@stu.thk.edu.tr

t. +90 541 741 2312

w. canturan10.github.io / linkedin.com/canturan10

# **EXPERIENCE**

#### Intern (Cyber Security) / Turkish Aerospace (TUSAŞ)

17/06/2019 – 12/07/2019, Ankara (Turkey)

Completion of a 1 month internship in the Cyber Security Unit and accordingly additional experience in the defense industry. Following the internship process, to make an informative presentation on the subjects in the research field. Gaining business experience that develops sectoral perspective.

#### Vice Chairman of the Board / IEEE UTAA Student Branch

01/06/2018 - 01/06/2019, Ankara (Turkey), ieeethku.com

Acting as the Vice Chairman of the Board and obtaining many management experiences such as project management and business follow-up.

# ● Intern (Software Architectural Design) / TÜBİTAK SAGE

10/06/2018 - 10/07/2018, Ankara (Turkey)

Completing his internship duty for 1 month in Software Architecture Design Unit and gaining experience in the Defense Industry sector. Following the internship process, making an informative presentation and reporting on topics in the research area. Contributing to the development of business awareness by being involved in the research and development process

# Chairman of Publicity and Design Committee / IEEE UTAA Student Branch

01/06/2017 - 01/06/2018 , Ankara (Turkey), ieeethku.com

For 1 year, the position of Chairman of the Publicity and Design Committee was completed, thus contributing to personal and professional development in terms of time management, teamwork, duty awareness and responsibility.

#### Intern / Grand National Assembly of Turkey (Turkish Parliament/TBMM)

01/09/2013 – 25/06/2014, Ankara (Turkey)

Completion of a 10-month compulsory internship at The Information Technology Unit in the Grand National Assembly of Turkey and thus gaining professional and personal awareness by acquiring experience of working in the state sector.

### ◆ Intern / Brighton MET (formerly City College Brighton and Hove)

04/03/2013 – 25/06/2013, Brighton (United Kingdom)

With a group of 6 people in the UK, he had the opportunity to take up vocational and language training for 4 months as well as internships. In this process, development was achieved in terms of becoming a citizen of the world, being positive about different nations and human relations.

#### **EDUCATIONS**

# Computer Engineering (English) / University of Turkish Aeronautical Association (Bachelor's Degree)

09/2015 – 07/2020 , Ankara (Turkey)

During his undergraduate education, he successfully completed the courses such as Formal Languages and Automata Theory, Computer Networks, Cryptography, Operating Systems, Statistical Computing, Data Analysis, Machine Learning and Artificial Intelligence, etc. and graduated as an Honor student.

# Information Technologies & English / Brighton MET (formerly City College Brighton and Hove)

03/2013 – 06/2013, Brighton (United Kingdom)

Within the scope of the Leonardo da Vinci Project, software (c#), database, computer mathematics and English courses have been successfully completed as the first of the department.



# PROFILE

After completing his primary and secondary education in Ankara, he continued his high school education in the field of information technologies in Ankara. During this period, internship experience was obtained in TBMM and the opportunity to study and do internship in Brigh ton, England for 4 months. This opportunity, which is the most important beginning of his career on computer, was successfully completed.

In 2015, he won the Department of Computer Engineering in the University of Turkish Aeronautical Association and graduated as an Honor student in 2020.

At the same time, as a freelancer, he works on different topics and enjoys supporting entrepreneurial people like himself.

# LANGUAGES

Turkish Mother tongue

English Proficiency (84) UTAA 2016

French

# MEMBERSHIPS

# IEEE

He started his career as a blogger and later served as the Chairman of the Promotion and Design Committee. 3 years when the student branch members, completed as Vice Chairman.

Member Number: 94367194

**Updated in July 2020** 

# CERTIFICATIONS

- Cryptography I / Stanford University
- Introduction to Cyber Attacks / New York
  University Tandon School of Engineering
- Palo Alto Networks Academy Cybersecurity
  Foundation / Palo Alto Networks
  09/2019
- Machine Learning / Stanford University
- Introduction to Data Science in Python /
  University of Michigan

03/2019

Fundamentals of Deep Learning for Computer Vision / Nvidia Deep Learning Institute

02/2019

Neural Networks and Deep Learning / deeplearning.ai

08/2018

Mobility Fundamentals / Cisco Networking
Academy

05/2018

Introduction to Cybersecurity / Cisco Networking Academy

05/2018

English and Vocational Training / City College Brighton and Hove

06/2013

Elementary & Pre Intermediate / British
School

11/2012

# REFERENCES

References on request will be forwarded to you.

#### **PROJECTS**

#### A system of Call Center Activities Supported by Artificial Intelligence / Senior Project 09/2019

This system, which works with the deep learning mechanism, will determine the performance of the operators by obtaining the appropriate data set for the language model and using this data set with the trained model after the speeches in the call centers are translated into text.

#### C-Rex

01/2019

It continues to be developed. A cyber security application that performs network scanning with interface experience is targeted.

### Meslek Seçerken

01/2019 - 01/2020

We have created a platform where our young brothers can hear their professional experiences from people who are experienced in their field in the process of choosing their profession and discovering their future.

# Ransomware / Academic Project

09/2019 - 12/2019

It was developed to create a conscious personnel model against ransomware. Education-oriented ransomware, after encrypting the victim's designated files with ChaCha20, shows the password with an instructive alert in the background.

### Classification / Academic Project

09/2019 - 12/2019

Developed to show the money needed to own a mobile phone with targeted features (such as battery power, camera, speed, ram). Price range classification was made using Naive Bayes.

#### ◆ SharEx - Share Experience / IEEEMadC

01/2019 - 12/2019

It was developed for the IEEE Mobile Application Competition. The app, which aims to provide mentoring services, appeals to all student users. The app is unique for many reasons, such as it is unbeatable on the market and easy to use.

# **♦** Bank/ATM Management System / Academic Project

09/2018 – 12/2018

A java application has been developed with an interface and a database connection where users can perform their basic functions.

# Studentship / INGBANK HACKATHON

11/201

We were able to complete the Android and web version of the application within 24 hours. The application we developed appeals to all student users. The application has the potential to quickly become popular among students, and it has opportunities such as scholarships and internships at its core.

# Leonardo Da Vinci Project

03/2013 – 06/2013

Deep Learning

The program aims to improve qualifications in vocational education systems and practices, to increase the knowledge, skills and competencies of individuals, and to promote innovation through trade unions across countries. Thanks to the Leonardo Da Vinci Project, the opportunity to do vocational and foreign language education as well as an internship was obtained in England within a period of 4 months.

# AREAS OF INTEREST

Cyber Security Data Science
Algorithms Android

Artificial Intelligence Augmented Reality

Machine Learning Virtual Reality